A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Correspondence Files FA1283
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Friends and Associates, 1962-1991; 2; 11.4 Cubic Feet 26 document boxes, 1 oversized flat box.
  - Personnel - Nunziato, Ralph J., 1964-1966 (Box 52, Folder 439)
  - Personnel - Thomas, Roy G., 1974-1975, 1980-1985 (Box 52, Folder 440)
    Thomas was Director of Horticulture at the Woodstock Inn. File includes 1981 memorandum on horticultural program for Woodstock.
  - Personnel - Tracy, Thomas N., [1967] (Box 52, Folder 441)
    File contains brief proposals for recreation development projects in southern California and Arizona.
  - Oversized Materials Separated from Boxes 33 - 51 (Box 73)
- Mail Log, 1962 - 1983, 1986; 3; 1.7 Cubic Feet 4.5 document boxes.
  The Mail Logs, which were maintained by LSR's office, provide a list of his incoming correspondence arranged by date received. The Logs note the correspondent's name, briefly describe the letter's subject matter and its disposition. Starting in April 1964, the logs also include the date of the letter. The Disposition column indicates the initials of the associate who handled the matter and/or notes action taken in response.
  The series also includes one log book for LSR correspondence pertaining to fundraising for Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center. The MSKCC log book primarily notes incoming correspondence, but also includes outgoing acknowledgements.
  LSR's mail logs for the period 1953-1961 are found in the LSR papers, RG 2, Office of the Messrs Rockefeller records (FA433), Series 1, box 5, folders 66-67, and box 62.
  - Mail Log, 1962-1968 (Box 53, Folder 442 - 450)
  - Mail Log, 1969 - 1976 June (Box 54, Folder 451 - 462)
  - Mail Log, 1976 July - 1980 June (Box 55, Folder 463 - 471)
  - Mail Log, 1980 July - 1983 (Box 56, Folder 472 - 479)
  - Mail Log, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 480 - 482)
    File marked "Closed Items," meaning not a restriction, but rather that the items are completed or require no further action.
  - Mail Log (Pending Items), 1986 July-December (Box 57, Folder 483)
  - MSKCC Correspondence Log Book, 1979 September - 1980 September (Box 57, Folder 484)
    File primarily concerns MSKCC's corporate fundraising campaign, and planning for the Sinatra benefit concert for MSKCC in January 1981. File consists of mail log (outgoing and incoming) and some copies of letters sent.
- Chronological Files, 1971, 1975-1986; 4; 5.1 Cubic Feet 13.5 document boxes.
  LSR's chronological files contain copies of LSR's outgoing correspondence, arranged by date. The files consist primarily of LSR's professional correspondence, though they also include personal notes and acknowledgments, and occasional memos to and/or from LSR's associates.
  A separate set of chronological files maintained by Carol S. LeBrecht for the period 1976 April - 1978 August has been added at the end of this series.
  - Chronological Files, 1971 September 17 - October (Box 57, Folder 485)
  - Chronological Files, 1971 September 17 - October (Box 70, Folder 485A)
  - Chronological Files, 1971 November - December (Box 57, Folder 486 - 488)
  - Chronological Files, 1975 January - May (Box 58, Folder 489 - 491)
  - Chronological Files, 1975 April - May (Box 70, Folder 491A)
  - Chronological Files, 1975 June - November (Box 58, Folder 492 - 495)
  - Chronological Files, 1975 October - November (Box 70, Folder 495A)
  - Chronological Files, 1975 December (Box 58, Folder 496)
  - Chronological Files, 1975 December (Box 70, Folder 496A)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 January - February (Box 58, Folder 497)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 January - February (Box 70, Folder 497A)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 March - April (Box 59, Folder 498 - 499)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 April (Box 70, Folder 499A)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 May (Box 59, Folder 500)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 May (Box 70, Folder 500A)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 June (Box 59, Folder 501)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 June (Box 70, Folder 501A)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 July - November (Box 59, Folder 502 - 505)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 November (Box 70, Folder 505A)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 December (Box 59, Folder 506)
  - Chronological Files, 1976 December (Box 70, Folder 506A)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 January (Box 60, Folder 507)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 January (Box 70, Folder 507A)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 February - March (Box 60, Folder 508 - 509)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 March (Box 70, Folder 509A)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 April - August (Box 60, Folder 510 - 513)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 August (Box 70, Folder 513A)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 September - December (Box 60, Folder 514 - 515)
  - Chronological Files, 1977 November - December (Box 70, Folder 515A)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 January - March (Box 61, Folder 516 - 518)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 March (Box 70, Folder 518A)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 April - May (Box 61, Folder 519)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 April - May (Box 70, Folder 519A)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 June (Box 61, Folder 520)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 June (Box 70, Folder 520A)
    Restricted - Confidential.
  - Chronological Files, 1978 July (Box 61, Folder 521)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 July (Box 70, Folder 521A)
  - Chronological Files, 1978 July 26-31 (Box 61, Folder 522-523)
    Correspondence mainly acknowledges condolences received on death of John D. Rockefeller 3.
  - Chronological Files, 1978 August - December (Box 62, Folder 524 - 527)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 January - February (Box 62, Folder 528)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 January - February (Box 70, Folder 528A)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 March - May (Box 62, Folder 529 - 530)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 May (Box 70, Folder 530A)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 June - July (Box 62, Folder 531 - 532)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 July (Box 70, Folder 532A)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 August (Box 63, Folder 533)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 August (Box 70, Folder 533A)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 September - October (Box 63, Folder 534)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 September - October (Box 70, Folder 534A)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 November - December (Box 63, Folder 535)
  - Chronological Files, 1979 November - December (Box 70, Folder 535A)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 January - February (Box 63, Folder 536 - 537)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 February (Box 70, Folder 537A)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 March - April (Box 63, Folder 538)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 March - April (Box 70, Folder 538A)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 May - June (Box 63, Folder 539)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 May - June (Box 70, Folder 539A)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 July (Box 63, Folder 540)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 July (Box 70, Folder 540A)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 August - September (Box 63, Folder 541)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 October - November (Box 64, Folder 542)
  - Chronological Files, 1980 December (Box 64, Folder 543)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 January - February (Box 64, Folder 544 - 545)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 February (Box 70, Folder 545A)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 March (Box 64, Folder 546)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 March (Box 70, Folder 546A)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 April - June (Box 64, Folder 547 - 549)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 June (Box 70, Folder 549A)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 July - August (Box 64, Folder 550)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 July - August (Box 70, Folder 550A)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 September - October (Box 64, Folder 551)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 September - October (Box 70, Folder 551A)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 November (Box 64, Folder 552)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 November (Box 70, Folder 552A)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 December (Box 65, Folder 553)
  - Chronological Files, 1981 December (Box 70, Folder 553A)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 January - April (Box 65, Folder 554 - 555)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 March - April (Box 70, Folder 555A)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 May - June (Box 65, Folder 556)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 May - June (Box 70, Folder 556A)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 July - Novemer (Box 65, Folder 557 - 560)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 November (Box 70, Folder 560A)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 December (Box 65, Folder 561)
  - Chronological Files, 1982 December (Box 70, Folder 561A)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 January (Box 65, Folder 562)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 January (Box 70, Folder 562A)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 February (Box 66, Folder 563)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 February (Box 70, Folder 563A)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 March - April (Box 66, Folder 564 - 565)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 April (Box 70, Folder 565A)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 May - July (Box 66, Folder 566 - 568)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 July (Box 70, Folder 568A)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 August - October (Box 66, Folder 569 - 570)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 October (Box 70, Folder 570A)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 November - December (Box 66, Folder 571 - 572)
  - Chronological Files, 1983 December (Box 70, Folder 572A)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 January - February (Box 67, Folder 573)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 January - February (Box 70, Folder 573A)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 March - June (Box 67, Folder 574 - 576)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 May - June (Box 70, Folder 576A)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 July (Box 67, Folder 577)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 July (Box 70, Folder 577A)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 August - September (Box 67, Folder 578)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 September (Box 70, Folder 578A)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 October (Box 67, Folder 579)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 October (Box 70, Folder 579A)
    Restricted. Material in the Rockefeller Family collections pertaining to living Rockefeller family members is restricted.
  - Chronological Files, 1984 November - December (Box 67, Folder 580)
  - Chronological Files, 1984 November - December (Box 70, Folder 580A)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 January (Box 67, Folder 581)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 January (Box 70, Folder 581A)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 February - March (Box 67, Folder 582)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 April (Box 68, Folder 583)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 April (Box 70, Folder 583A)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 May - June (Box 68, Folder 584)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 May - June (Box 70, Folder 584A)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 July (Box 68, Folder 585)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 July (Box 70, Folder 585A)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 August - October (Box 68, Folder 586 - 587)
    Folder 587 includes incoming letters and acknowledgments concerning LSR's gift to MSKCC for the Rockefeller Research Laboratories.
  - Chronological Files, 1985 October (Box 70, Folder 587A)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 November - December (Box 68, Folder 588 - 589)
  - Chronological Files, 1985 December (Box 70, Folder 589A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 January (Box 68, Folder 590)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 January (Box 70, Folder 590A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 February (Box 68, Folder 591)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 March (Box 69, Folder 592)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 March (Box 70, Folder 592A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 April (Box 69, Folder 593)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 April (Box 70, Folder 593A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 May (Box 69, Folder 594)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 May (Box 70, Folder 594A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 June - July (Box 69, Folder 595 - 596)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 July (Box 70, Folder 596A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 August (Box 69, Folder 597)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 August (Box 70, Folder 597A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 September (Box 69, Folder 598)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 September (Box 70, Folder 598A)
  - Chronological Files, 1986 October (Box 69, Folder 599)
  - Chronological Files (Carol S. LeBrecht), 1976 April - 1978 August (Box 69, Folder 600 - 601)
    This set of Chronological Files was maintained by LSR's assistant Carol S. LeBrecht. Contents were originally housed in a prong binder (found in LSR Accession 2008:060).
    It is not known how this file compares in contents to the other chronological files for this period.
- Special Letters, 1948, 1959-1986; 5; .8 Cubic Feet 1 half-size document box, 1 oversized album case.
  Series consists of two "Special Letters" albums, one of which has been disbound and rehoused in archival folders. Selected letters of recognition and appreciation from prominent figures, friends, and family.
  - Special Letters Album - A - Z, 1968-1986 (Box 71, Folder 602)
    Letters removed from a magnetic photo album, in which they had been arranged and interfiled in chronological order with the letters now found in Lady Bird Johnson file. The current alphabetical arrangement was adopted when the album was disbanded.
    Correspondents represented: Albert of Monaco; Tom Brokaw; Warren E. Burger; John G. Burnett; Barbara Bush and George H. W. Bush, 1982, 1985-1986; Rosalynn Carter and Jimmy Carter, 1979, 1983-1984; Mario Cuomo; Malcolm R. Doak; Gerald R. Ford, 1982-1984, 1986; Arthur Godfrey; J. Peter Grace; Hubert H. Humphrey; Luci Johnson; Henry A. Kissinger; Edward Koch; Orin Lehman; Dina Merrill; Joan Mondale; Richard Nixon, 1983-1984; Norman Vincent Peale; Anna Perry-Fiske; Ronald and Nancy Reagan; Lynda Johnson Robb; Happy Rockefeller; Rodman Rockefeller; Alan K. Simpson; Barbara Sinatra; Lewis Thomas.
  - Special Letters Album - A - Z, 1979, 1983 (Box 71, Folder 602 A)
  - Special Letters Album - Lady Bird Johnson, 1969, 1977-1986 (Box 71, Folder 603)
    Letters removed from a magnetic photo album, in which they had been arranged and interfiled in chronological order with the letters now found in the A-Z file. The current alphabetical arrangement was adopted when the album was disbound.
  - Special Letters Album, 1948, 1959 - 1982; Post-bound album enclosed in clamshell case, 15.25" x 14.25" x 4.5". Letters tipped in to album pages. (Box 72)
    Album of letters from prominent national figures and personal friends. Letters of appreciation for stays at LSR's resorts in the Caribbean (Dorado Beach, Caneel Bay) and Hawaii (Mauna Kea) make up a large proportion of the letters, but recognition of LSR's contributions relating to conservation, outdoor recreation, and the environment, and the fight against cancer, are other signficant themes. "LSR" engraved on album cover.